benefitaccess.com 2014-11-18

# Privacy Notice

Privacy Notice
This privacy notice describes the U.S. privacy policy of Morgan Stanley Smith Barney LLC (“us,” “our” or “we”).   Personal Questions
   We are required by federal law to provide you with notice of our U.S. privacy policy (“Policy”). This Policy
applies to both our current and former clients unless we state otherwise and is intended for individual clients   1. What personal
who purchase products or receive services from us for personal, family or household purposes. This Policy         information do we
is not applicable to partnerships, corporations, trusts or other non-individual clients or account holders, nor   collect about you?
is this Policy applicable to individuals who are either beneficiaries of a trust for which we serve as trustee or
                                                                                                                  2. When do we disclose
participants in an employee benefit plan administered or advised by us. This Policy is, however, applicable
                                                                                                                  personal information
to individuals who select us to be a custodian of securities or assets in individual retirement accounts, 401(k)
                                                                                                                  we collect about you?
accounts, or accounts subject to the Uniform Gifts to Minors Act.
   This notice sets out our business practices to protect your privacy; how we collect and share personal         3. How do we protect
information about you; and how you can limit our sharing or certain uses by others of this information. We        the security and
may amend our Policy at any time, and will inform you of any changes to our Policy as required by law.            confidentiality of
We Respect Your Privacy                                                                                           personal information
                                                                                                                  we collect about you?
We appreciate that you have provided us with your personal financial information and understand your
concerns about your information. We continue to follow the long-standing commitment to safeguard the              4. How can you limit our
information our clients entrust to us. Protecting the confidentiality and security of client information is an    sharing certain personal
important part of how we conduct our business.                                                                    information about
   This notice describes what personal information we collect about you, how we collect it, when we may           you with our affiliated
share it with others, and how certain others may use it. It discusses the steps you may take to limit our shar-   companies for eligibility
ing of certain information about you with our affiliated companies, including but not limited to our affiliated   determination?
investment management businesses, our banking businesses and our credit services affiliates. It also discloses
how you may limit our affiliates’ use of shared information for marketing purposes.                               5. How can you limit
   Throughout this notice, we refer to the nonpublic information that personally identifies you as “personal      the use of certain
information.” We also use the term “affiliated company” in this notice. An affiliated company is a company in     personal information
our family of companies, and includes companies with the Morgan Stanley name. These affiliated companies          about you by our
are financial institutions, such as broker-dealers, banks, and credit card issuers. We refer to any company       affiliated companies
that is not an affiliated company as a nonaffiliated third party.                                                 for marketing?
    For purposes of Section 5 of this notice, and your ability to limit certain uses of personal information by
our affiliates, this notice applies to the use of personal information by our affiliated companies.               6. How can you send us
                                                                                                                  an opt-out instruction?
1. What personal information do we collect about you?
We may collect the following types of personal information about you: (i) information provided by you,            7. What if an affiliated
including information from applications and other forms we receive from you, (ii) information about your          company becomes
transactions with us or our affiliates, (iii) information about your transactions with nonaffiliated third par-   a nonaffiliated
ties, (iv) information from consumer reporting agencies, (v) information obtained from our websites, and          third party?
(vi) information obtained from other sources.
    For example:
        We collect information such as your name, address, email address, telephone/fax numbers, assets,
         income and investment objectives through applications and other forms you submit to us.
       We may obtain information about account balances, your use of account(s) and the types of
         products and services you prefer to receive from us through your dealings and transactions with
         us and other sources.

         e may obtain information about your creditworthiness
        W                                                              that comply with applicable law and regulations to help safeguard
        and credit history from consumer reporting agencies.           the personal information we collect about you. We have internal
       We may collect background information from and through         policies governing the proper handling of client information by
        third-party vendors to verify representations you have         employees. Third parties that provide support or marketing services
        made and to comply with various regulatory requirements.       on our behalf may also receive personal information about you, and
                                                                       we require them to adhere to appropriate security standards with
2. When do we disclose personal information we collect
                                                                       respect to such information.
about you?
We may disclose personal information we collect about you in each      4. How can you limit our sharing certain personal informa-
of the categories listed above to affiliated companies and to nonaf-   tion about you with our affiliated companies for eligibility
filiated third parties.                                                determination?
    a. Information we disclose to affiliated companies                 By following the opt-out procedures in Section 6, below, you may
    We may disclose personal information that we collect about you     limit the extent to which we share with our affiliated companies
to our affiliated companies, which include both financial service      personal information that was collected to determine your eligibil-
providers and non-financial companies, for a variety of reasons,       ity for products and services such as your credit reports and other
including to manage your account(s) effectively, to service and        information that you have provided to us or that we may obtain from
process your transactions, to let you know about products and          third parties (“eligibility information”). Eligibility information does
services offered by us and our affiliated companies, to manage our     not include your identification information or personal information
business, and as otherwise required or permitted by law. Offers for    pertaining to our transactions or experiences with you. Please note
products and services from our affiliated companies are developed      that, even if you direct us not to share eligibility information with
under conditions designed to safeguard your personal information.      our affiliated companies, we may still share your personal informa-
    b. Information we disclose to nonaffiliated third parties          tion, including eligibility information, with our affiliated companies
    We may disclose personal information that we collect about         under circumstances that are permitted under applicable law, such
you to nonaffiliated third parties, which include both financial       as to process transactions or to service your account.
service providers and non-financial companies. We may disclose
                                                                       5. How can you limit the use of certain personal information
all of the information we collect, as described above, to companies    about you by our affiliated companies for marketing?
that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other financial
                                                                       By following the opt-out instructions in Section 6, below, you may
institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements. We
                                                                       limit our affiliated companies from marketing their products or
may also disclose all of the information we collect to other non-
                                                                       services to you based on personal information we disclose to them.
affiliated third parties for our everyday business purposes, such
                                                                       This information may include, for example, your income and your
as to process transactions, maintain account(s), respond to court
                                                                       account history with us. Please note that, even if you choose to
orders and legal investigations, report to credit bureaus, offer our
                                                                       limit our affiliated companies from using personal information
own products and services, protect against fraud, for institutional
                                                                       about you that we may share with them for marketing their prod-
risk control, to perform services on our behalf, and as otherwise
                                                                       ucts and services to you, our affiliated companies may use your
required or permitted by law.
                                                                       personal information that they obtain from us to market to you in
    For Morgan Stanley Wealth Management clients, we recognize
                                                                       circumstances permitted by law, such as if the affiliated party has
that your relationship with your Financial Advisor or Private Wealth
                                                                       its own relationship with you.
Advisor is important. If your Financial Advisor or Private Wealth
Advisor’s affiliation with us ends and he or she joins a nonaffiliated 6. How can you send us an opt-out instruction?
securities broker-dealer with which we have entered into an agree-     If you wish to limit our sharing of eligibility information about you
ment limiting the use of information, we will permit your Financial    with our affiliated companies, or our affiliated companies’ use of
Advisor or Private Wealth Advisor to retain certain of your contact    personal information for marketing purposes, as described in this
information, limited to your name, address, email address, phone       notice, you may do so by:
number and account title. Other than the disclosure described in         • Calling us at 1-800-295-1460.
this paragraph or as otherwise required or permitted by law, we do       • Sending an email to privacy-optout@morganstanley.com, or
not disclose any personal information about our former customers.        •W riting to us at the following address:
    When we share personal information about you with a nonaf-             Morgan Stanley
filiated third party, they are required to limit their use of personal     Client Correspondence Department
information about you to the particular purpose for which it was           PO Box 95002
shared and they are not allowed to share personal information about        South Jordan, UT 84095
you with others except to fulfill that limited purpose or as may be
                                                                          If you choose to email or write to us, your request should include
permitted or required by law.
                                                                       your name, address, telephone number and account number(s) to
3. How do we protect the security and confidentiality of               which the opt-out applies and whether you are opting out with
personal information we collect about you?                             respect to sharing of eligibility information (Section 4 above), or
We maintain physical, electronic and procedural security measures      information used for marketing (Section 5 above), or both. Written

opt-out requests should not be sent with any other correspondence.                 other than those who are providing you this notice, you may receive
In order to process your request, we require that the request be                   multiple privacy notices from them. You will need to separately
provided by you directly and not through a third party. Once you                   notify those companies of your privacy choices for those accounts
have informed us about your privacy preferences, your opt-out                      or relationships.
preference will remain in effect with respect to our Policy (as it
                                                                                   7. What if an affiliated company becomes a nonaffiliated
may be amended) until you notify us otherwise. If you are a joint
                                                                                   third party?
account owner, we will accept instructions from any one of you
                                                                                   If, at any time in the future, an affiliated company becomes a nonaf-
and apply those instructions to the entire account.
                                                                                   filiated third party, further disclosures of personal information made
  Please understand that if you limit our sharing or our affiliated
                                                                                   to the former affiliated company will be limited to those described
companies’ use of personal information, you and any joint account
                                                                                   in Section 2(b) above relating to nonaffiliated third parties. If you
holder(s) may not receive information about our affiliated com-
                                                                                   elected under Section 6 to limit disclosures we make to affiliated
panies’ products and services, including products or services that
                                                                                   companies, or use of personal information by affiliated companies,
could help you manage your financial resources and achieve your
                                                                                   your election will not apply to use by any former affiliated company
investment objectives.
                                                                                   of your personal information in their possession once it becomes
  If you have more than one account or relationship with us, please
                                                                                   a nonaffiliated third party.
specify the accounts to which you would like us to apply your privacy
choices. If you have accounts or relationships with our affiliates,
           special notice to residents of vermont
           The following section supplements our Policy with respect to our individual clients who have a Vermont address and supersedes anything
           to the contrary in the above Policy with respect to those clients only.
           The state of Vermont requires financial institutions to obtain your consent prior to sharing personal information that they collect about
           you with nonaffiliated third parties, or eligibility information with affiliated companies, other than in certain limited circumstances.
           Except as permitted by law, we will not share personal information we collect about you with nonaffiliated third parties, or eligibility
           information with affiliated companies, unless you provide us with your written consent to share such information.
           special notice to residents of california
           The following section supplements our Policy with respect to our individual clients who have a California address and supersedes
           anything to the contrary in the above Policy with respect to those clients only.
           In response to a California law, if your account has a California home address, your personal information will not be disclosed to
           nonaffiliated third parties except as permitted by applicable California law, and we will limit sharing such personal information with
           our affiliates to comply with California privacy laws that apply to us.
           Do Not Track Policy
           We do not engage in the collection of personal information about your online activities over time and across third-party Web sites or
           online services and do not allow third parties to collect personal information about your online activities over time and across third-
           party Web sites when you use our online services. We do not respond to Web browser “do not track signals.”
© 2014 Morgan Stanley Smith Barney LLC. Member SIPC.                    Effective Date: January 1, 2014                                       CS 7783795 01/14
